
[
    {
           "question": "Which is the only mammal that canâ€™t jump?",
           "optionA": "Dog",
           "optionB": "Elephant",
           "optionC": "Goat",
           "optionD": "Lion",
           "answer": "Elephant"
       },

       {
        "question": "Which the name of Iron man?",
           "optionA": "Bruce",
           "optionB": "Peter Parker",
           "optionC": "Steve Rogers",
           "optionD": "Tony Stark",
           "answer": "Tony Stark"
        
       },

       {
        "question": "What is the capital of India?",
           "optionA": "Mumbai",
           "optionB": "Delhi",
           "optionC": "New Delhi",
           "optionD": "Kolkata",
           "answer": "New Delhi"
        
       },

       {
        "question": "Who Gave '0' to world?",
           "optionA": "Aryabhata",
           "optionB": "Albert Einstein",
           "optionC": "Newton",
           "optionD": "None of the above",
           "answer": "Aryabhata"
        
       },
   
       {
        "question": "What is the National Bird of India?",
           "optionA": "Peacock",
           "optionB": "Pigeons",
           "optionC": "Parrots",
           "optionD": "Owl",
           "answer": "Peacock"
        
       },
    
       {
        "question": "Which was the first fully color film of India?",
           "optionA": "aan",
           "optionB": "King Harishchandra",
           "optionC": "Alamara",
           "optionD": "Rani of Jhansi",
           "answer": "Rani of Jhansi"
        
       },
    
       {
        "question": "Which Gupta king was also known as Vikramaditya?",
           "optionA": "Samudragupta",
           "optionB": "Kumaragupta",
           "optionC": "Chandragupta I",
           "optionD": "Chandragupta II",
           "answer": "Chandragupta II"
        
       },
   
       {
        "question": "Dandi March started on ?",
           "optionA": "March 10, 1930",
           "optionB": "March 12, 1930",
           "optionC": "March 10, 1931",
           "optionD": "March 12, 1931",
           "answer": "March 12, 1930"
        
       },
   
    {
        "question": "The largest part of the human brain part is?",
           "optionA": "Cerebellum",
           "optionB": "Midbrain",
           "optionC": "Cerebrum",
           "optionD": "Medulla Oblongata",
           "answer": "Cerebrum"
        
       },
   
    {
        "question": "The famous ruler of ancient India who adopted Jainism in the last days of his life-",
           "optionA": "Chandragupta Maurya",
           "optionB": "Ashok",
           "optionC": "Samudragupta",
           "optionD": "Bindusara",
           "answer": "Chandragupta Maurya"
        
       },
    
    {
        "question": " Whose name was also 'Dewan Piyadashi' Who among the following is the person?",
           "optionA": "Ashok",
           "optionB": "Chandragupta",
           "optionC": "Gautam Buddha",
           "optionD": "Mahavir",
           "answer": "Ashok"
        
       },
    {
        "question": "Who first used the word 'Swaraj' among the following?",
           "optionA": "Swami Dayanand Saraswati",
           "optionB": "Raja Rammohan Roy",
           "optionC": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
           "optionD": "Bhagat Singh",
           "answer": "Swami Dayanand Saraswati"
        
       },
   
    {
        "question": "Who was called Peshwa in Shivaji's administration?",
           "optionA": "Raksha Mantri",
           "optionB": "Minister of Religious Affairs",
           "optionC": "Chief Minister",
           "optionD": "Justice",
           "answer": "Chief Minister"
        
       },
    
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the oldest monument?",
           "optionA": "Qutubminar",
           "optionB": "Taj Mahal",
           "optionC": "Ajanta Caves",
           "optionD": "Khajuraho",
           "answer": "Ajanta Caves"
        
       },
   
    {
        "question": "Whose period is called the golden period of Mughal architecture?",
           "optionA": "Akbar",
           "optionB": "Jahangir",
           "optionC": "Shah Jahan",
           "optionD": "Aurangzeb",
           "answer": "Shah Jahan"
        
       }

   ]